<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Free software | Connor Mendenhall]]></title>
  <link href="http://ecmendenhall.github.io/blog/categories/free-software/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ecmendenhall.github.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-05T16:13:05-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://ecmendenhall.github.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Connor Mendenhall]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ecmendenhall@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open web security essentials]]></title>
    <link href="http://ecmendenhall.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/30/open-web-security-essentials/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-30T00:08:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ecmendenhall.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/30/open-web-security-essentials</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past two weeks, I've been working through <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Web-Application-Hackers-Handbook/dp/1118026470">The Web Application
Hacker's
Handbook</a>.
Although it's not part of the 8th Light core curriculum, it ought to
be: it's a comprehensive catalog of web security mistakes and a great
introduction to thinking about vulnerabilities from an attacker's perspective. The only gripe I have
with the authors is their penchant for plugging expensive closed-source software
and online training. Fortunately, I've found plenty of free
alternatives. Here are a few of the essential tools I've found for
developers interested in web security.</p>

<h2>VirtualBox</h2>

<p>Every tool in my pentesting kit depends on
<a href="https://www.virtualbox.org/">VirtualBox</a>. Working in virtual machines
keeps my security tools separate from my development environment, and
allows me to practice attacking hideously vulnerable applications in
quarantine. VirtualBox includes excellent network configuration
options, including completely virtualized local networks that make it
easy to keep things compartmentalized.</p>

<h2>Kali Linux</h2>

<p><a href="http://www.kali.org/">Kali Linux</a>, formerly BackTrack, is a
specialized Debian distribution that includes hundreds of built in
security tools. I can't begin to imagine the time I might have spent
with Homebrew installing and configuring everything included here. The tools included with Kali are many and powerful, and
I've discovered a new fuzzer, proxy, or scanner to try for every topic
in the book.</p>

<h2>Zed Attack Proxy</h2>

<p>The authors of WAHH frequently plug their own Burp Suite, a closed-source
intercepting proxy that costs $300 per user per year to do anything
useful. <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/OWASP_Zed_Attack_Proxy_Project">Zed Attack
Proxy</a>,
developed by the <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Main_Page">Open Web Security
Project</a>, is completely free, Apache
licensed, and just as good an educational and testing tool.
(It's included in Kali, along with the free
edition of Burp). Hacking tools are not always the most carefully
crafted software, but ZAP is an extremely stable, very pleasant
exception. <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/WebScarab_Getting_Started">WebScarab</a>, also by OWASP, is another good free alternative.</p>

<h2>SQLMap</h2>

<p>I remember the joy of my first successful SQL injection like it was
last Thursday. (It <em>was</em> last Thursday, but that's beside the point).
The thrill of breaking in with a well placed apostrophe and couple of
dashes takes a while to wear off, but diminishing returns are likely to
set in after 50 handcrafted variations on the same GET parameter.
Fortunately, there's
<a href="https://github.com/sqlmapproject/sqlmap">SQLMap</a>, which almost makes
it too easy, automating the entire process of finding and exploiting SQL injection vulnerabilities.</p>

<p>All these tools are no fun without something to (safely, responsibly, legally)
attack. Browsing through WAHH, I was excited to see lots of links to
online interactive labs illustrating almost every concept. I was less
excited to discover that they're completely proprietary and cost
$7/hour. Fortunately, there are plenty of open alternatives:</p>

<h2>Metasploitable</h2>

<p><a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/metasploitable/files/Metasploitable2/">Metasploitable2</a>
is an intentionally vulnerable virtual machine configured to run
several vulnerable web applications on port 80 by default, including
<a href="http://www.dvwa.co.uk/">Damn Vulnerable Web App</a> and
<a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/OWASP_Mutillidae_2_Project">Mutillidae</a>.
Before booting it up, please make sure your network settings are
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e0vpBKRZPGc">configured
correctly</a>: it should
never ever be exposed to users on your network or the internet.</p>

<h2>RailsGoat</h2>

<p>I'm not reading WAHH to become a professional pentester. I'm doing it
to learn how to develop safe web applications, and we write lots of
them in Rails. <a href="https://github.com/OWASP/railsgoat">RailsGoat</a> (yet
another OWASP project) is a vulnerable Rails application with built-in
documentation and examples of the <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10_2013-Top_10">top
10</a> web
vulnerabilities. Best of all, each one includes code samples, which
are especially useful for a developer like me trying to avoid writing
a goat of my own.</p>

<h2>OWASP</h2>

<p>Many of these resources come courtesy of OWASP, the <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Main_Page">Open Web
Application Security
Project</a>. In addition to
developing lots of free tools, they're an excellent resource for
learning about web security.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
