<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: TDD, | Connor Mendenhall]]></title>
  <link href="http://ecmendenhall.github.io/blog/categories/tdd/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ecmendenhall.github.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-04T14:34:08-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://ecmendenhall.github.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Connor Mendenhall]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ecmendenhall@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shitty first drafts]]></title>
    <link href="http://ecmendenhall.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/10/shitty-first-drafts/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-10T01:03:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ecmendenhall.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/10/shitty-first-drafts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>"Very few writers really know what they are doing until they've done it. Nor do
they go about their business feeling dewy and thrilled. They do not type a few stiff
warm-up sentences and then find themselves bounding along like huskies across the
snow. One writer I know tells me that he sits down every morning and says to
himself nicely, "It's not like you don't have a choice, because you do -- you can
either type, or kill yourself." We all often feel like we are pulling teeth, even those
writers whose prose ends up being the most natural and fluid. The right words and
sentences just do not come pouring out like ticker tape most of the time. […] For me and
most of the other writers I know, writing is not rapturous. In fact, the only way I can get
anything written at all is to write really, really shitty first drafts."</p></blockquote>

<p>–Anne Lamott on <a href="http://wrd.as.uky.edu/sites/default/files/1-Shitty%20First%20Drafts.pdf">shitty first drafts</a>, from <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Bird-Some-Instructions-Writing-Life/dp/0385480016/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1370844305&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=bird+by+bird"><em>Bird By Bird</em></a></p>

<p>This is supposed to be a professional blog, but I hope you'll pardon
this bit of language, which comes with some of the best and dearest
 advice on professionalism I've read.</p>

<p>At the end of last week, I moved on to the second project of my
  apprenticeship: writing a simple HTTP server from scratch.
  Starting the project was not rapturous. I knew the basics—model the
  filesystem, connect over a socket, and transfer specially-formatted
  text back and forth—but had no idea where to start or what test to
  write first. I read up on sockets, browsed through the HTTP spec,
  and stared dumbly into IntelliJ for a while, and at long last, I
  started typing. What Anne Lamott calls "shitty first drafts" the TDD
  world calls
  <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/249969/why-are-tdd-spikes-called-spikes">"spikes"</a>—short
  experiments, sometimes without tests, to figure out what to work on
  next. A spike is like a "child's draft," allowed to run wild and
  break things on condition that it will be thrown out and replaced
  with something decent (and well-tested).</p>

<p>Of course, as soon as I had a few lines of code down, the ideas
  started to flow (I started by parsing headers, by the way), and
  within an hour I had a feature-complete <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hyper_Text_Coffee_Pot_Control_Protocol">HTCPCP server</a> (HTTP is still a work in progress). Another reminder that programming is craft, and writing code really is a creative act.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
