<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: privacy | Connor Mendenhall]]></title>
  <link href="http://ecmendenhall.github.io/blog/categories/privacy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ecmendenhall.github.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-14T09:26:42-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://ecmendenhall.github.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Connor Mendenhall]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ecmendenhall@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DIY Gmail with sup]]></title>
    <link href="http://ecmendenhall.github.io/blog/blog/2013/08/04/diy-gmail-with-sup/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-04T15:20:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ecmendenhall.github.io/blog/blog/2013/08/04/diy-gmail-with-sup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been a Gmail user for my entire adult life. Ever since I
abandoned my old AOL inbox on the family PC, Gmail has simply <em>been</em>
email. I've never used folders, only labels. I've never deleted
old messages to save space, but archived everything. I've always
expected full-text search, aggressive spam filtering, and continuous
access from any device.</p>

<p>As I've archived year after year of new messages, I've become less
comfortable storing my entire indexed email history on someone else's
servers, where they can be scanned and
<a href="https://ssd.eff.org/3rdparties/govt/stronger-protection">searched</a> at
will. And yet in practice , I've always traded off privacy against
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dBtmzY5gcO8">convention</a> and
<a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2013/06/trading_privacy_1.html">convenience</a>.</p>

<p>In part, this is because it's long been a discontinuous decision: even a
small amount of extra control or privacy required giving up all the
modern conveniences of webmail at once. No desktop client came close to the features of Gmail, so I never made the switch. But now that
I spend most of my time in a terminal, I've finally found a client
that provides a pretty good compromise: <a href="http://supmua.org/">sup</a>.</p>

<p>Sup is not something I'd set up for my Mom, but Rubyists and Unix
geeks will feel right at home. It's a
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Curses_(programming_library)">curses</a>
based mail client written in Ruby with excellent full text search out
of the box. In addition to offering archiving, labels, and search,
it's built on top of extensible tools like offlineimap, msmtp, and gpg, and
scriptable in Ruby.</p>

<p>The official docs are very good (and thus don't need to be repeated),
but these are the sections I found most helpful in order:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/sup-heliotrope/sup/wiki/Mac-OSX">OS X
installation</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/sup-heliotrope/sup/wiki/Mac-OSX">Gmail
configuration</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/sup-heliotrope/sup/wiki/Adding-sources">Storing messages in Maildirs</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/sup-heliotrope/sup/wiki/Securely-Store-Password">Secure password
storage</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/sup-heliotrope/sup/wiki/gpg">GPG integration</a></li>
</ul>


<p>For now, sup doesn't do two-way IMAP syncing, so messages I archive
stay on my machine. In my case this is a feature, not a bug: I now
have a permanent searchable archive stored locally that won't change
if I delete messages from my Gmail account. I can keep the last few
weeks of mail on the Gmail server, accessible from my phone and the web (and seriously, when
was the last time you looked at an email more than a month old?), and
everything else securely archived on my own drive.</p>

<p>It would be a mistake to consider my sup setup much more private than
plain Gmail. My messages still travel across the internet in cleartext and pile up
in my correspondents' inboxes. (Sup integrates nicely with GPG for
ad hoc encryption). They're probably still stored in <a href="https://www.quora.com/Gmail/Does-gmail-delete-the-deleted-emails-forever">Google
backups</a>
and no doubt snarfed and <a href="http://www.wired.com/threatlevel/2012/03/ff_nsadatacenter/">sent off to
Bluffdale</a>.
I am probably not paranoid enough, but I believe Google's claims that they really do erase deleted
messages, and keeping my own archive raises the cost of compromising
or reconstructing my entire history by a little bit, without
sacrificing the features I've become so dependent upon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
